Morris Lapidus Papers
Morris Lapidus Papers
- Professional papers
  - Projects
    - Americana Hotel (New York, New York)
      - Drawings, floor plans (Oversize 7)
      - Photographs, black and white and color (Box 9)
    - Americana Hotel (San Juan, Puerto Rico)
      - Drawings, includes site and floor plans (Oversize 7)
      - Photographs, black and white (Box 9)
    - Andros Island / Inter-Bahamas Clubdominium (Bahamas), color photographs of renderings (Oversize 5)
    - Ansonia store (Miami Beach, Florida), black and white photographs and photocopy (Box 9)
    - Arawak Hotel (Jamaica)
      - Drawings, floor plans (one has a black and white photograph attached) (Oversize 7)
      - Photographs, black and white with one color photograph of drawing (Box 9)
    - Arlen Beach Hotel (Miami Beach, Florida), black and white photographs (Box 9)
    - Armstrong's showroom, 1933; black and white photograph (Box 9)
    - Aura (Miami, Florida), 1999; undated; color photographs and press materials (Box 9)
    - Aruba Caribbean Hotel (Aruba)
      - Drawings, includes perspective view, site plan and floor plans (Oversize 7)
      - Photographs, black and white, includes some transparencies and photocopies (Box 9)
      - Photographs, oversize black and white (Oversize 5)
    - Aventura Hotel (North Miami, Florida), circa 1969; black and white photograph (Box 9)
    - Barton's Candy Shop, black and white photographs and photocopy (Box 9)
    - Beaunit Mills (New York, New York), black and white photograph (Box 9)
    - Beck Shoes, black and white photographs and photocopy (Box 9)
    - Bedford-Stuyvesant pool (Brooklyn, New York), black and white and color photographs (Box 9)
    - The Beehive (Catchogue, New York), 1955; undated; black and white photographs (Box 9)
    - Bender's office building (Washington, DC), black and white photograph of rendering (Box 9)
    - Biscayne office building (Miami, Florida), color photographs (Box 9)
    - Blair Towers (Baltimore, Maryland), 1959; black and white photographs (Box 9)
    - Boatel (New Port Richey, Florida), drawings include site plan, floor plans and elevations (Oversize 7)
    - Bon Bini (St. Martin, Virgin Islands), black and white photograph (Box 9)
    - Bond store, 1947-1949; undated; black and white photographs (Box 9)
    - Bond store (Chicago, Illinois), black and white and color photographs (Box 9)
    - Bond store (Cincinnati, Ohio), black and white photographs (Box 9)
    - Bond store (New York, New York), 1948; undated; black and white and color photographs (Box 9)
    - Bostonian Shoes (Chicago, Illinois), 1940; undated; black and white photographs (Box 9)
    - Broadway Maintenance (New York, New York), 1948; black and white photograph (Box 9)
    - Causeway Motel (Tampa, Florida)
      - Drawings, floor plans (Oversize 7)
      - Photographs, 1960; undated; black and white (Box 9)
    - Chalk House (Washington, DC), 1966; undated; black and white photographs (Box 9)
    - Chicopee Hotel (Chicopee, Massachusetts)
      - Drawing, master plan (Oversize 7)
      - Photographs, black and white photographs (Box 9)
    - Citizens' Federal (Miami, Florida), 1974; 1980,; undated; black and white and color photographs (Box 9)
    - Colonial Plaza Motel (Orlando, Florida), black and white photographs (Box 9)
    - Concord Hotel (Kraniesha Lake, New York), black and white photographs (Box 9)
    - Concordia Gardens (Puerto Rico), black and white photograph (Box 9)
    - El Conquistador Hotel (Fajardo, Puerto Rico), 1970; black and white and color photographs, photocopy (Box 9)
    - Continental restaurant (Paramus, New Jersey), 1957; undated; black and white photographs (Box 9)
    - Crescent Park (East Orange, New Jersey), 1966; undated; black and white photographs (Box 9)
    - Crystal House (Miami Beach, Florida), 1960-1962; undated; black and white photographs and color photograph of rendering (Box 9)
    - Crystal Motors (Brooklyn, New York), 1948; black and white photograph (Box 9)
    - Cuff links, auctioneer's catalogue featuring cuff links designed by Lapidus (Box 9)
    - Dade office building, color photograph of rendering (Box 9)
    - Daniel Tower Hotel (Hertselea, Israel), black and white and color photographs (Box 10)
    - Development homes T. Huntington, black and white photograph (Box 10)
    - Dilido Hotel (Miami Beach, Florida), black and white photographs and photocopies (Box 10)
    - Distilled Spirits Institute, 1939 New York World's Fair (New York, New York)
      - Photographs, 1939; black and white (Box 10)
      - Photographs, 1939; oversize black and white photograph of model (Oversize 5)
    - The Dorchester (Boca Raton, Florida), black and white photographs of renderings (Box 10)
    - Doubleday Doran Book Shops, 1932; black and white photograph (Box 10)
    - Douglas Shoe Company, black and white photographs (Box 10)
    - Dutch Inn (Atlanta, Georgia), color photograph of rendering (Box 10)
    - E Street office building (Washington, DC), 1966; black and white photographs (Box 10)
    - Eden Roc Hotel (Miami Beach, Florida)
      - Color renderings (Oversize 5)
      - Drawings, floor plans, includes black and white photograph of Harry's bar (Oversize 7)
      - Photographs, 1954-1955; undated; black and white and color, includes transparencies and photographs of renderings (Box 10)
    - Edward's Shoes (Washington, DC), 1949; color photograph (Box 10)
    - Executive House apartment hotel (Chicago, Illinois), black and white photographs (Box 10)
    - Eymer and Amand, 1934; black and white photograph (Box 10)
    - Fairfield Towers (Brooklyn, New York), 1966; black and white photographs (Box 10)
    - Fairview Country Club (Greenwich, Connecticut), 1968; black and white photograph (Box 10)
    - Finn / Eiber residence
      - E. B. A.I.A. Eiber House 1960 [photographs], lapidus_69; CD (Box 10)
      - Photographs, oversize black and white of drawings (Oversize 5)
    - Florsheim Shoes, circa 1932; black and white photographs (Box 10)
    - Fortuna Beach Hotel (Fajardo, Puerto Rico), photostats of drawings include aerial perspective, site plans and floor plans (Oversize 7)
    - Fontainebleau hotel (Miami Beach, Florida)
      - Drawings, includes floor plans and perspective sketch (Oversize 7)
      - Photographs, black and white and color, includes black and white photographs of renderings and photocopies; 2 folders (Box 10)
    - Forsythe Shoes, 1929; black and white photographs (Box 10)
    - Furniture designs, sketches, computer printouts, etc. (Box 10)
    - Furniture promotional materials, 2 folders (Box 11)
    - G Street office building (Washington, DC), circa 1963; black and white photograph (Box 11)
    - George and Lester's clothing store, black and white photograph (Box 11)
    - Golden Triangle Hotel (Norfolk, Virginia), black and white photographs (Box 11)
    - Gombe Hotel (Nigeria), color photograph of rendering (Box 11)
    - Gussman Olympic Theater (Miami, Florida), color photograph (Box 11)
    - Hamilton House apartment (Miami, Florida), black and white photographs (Box 11)
    - Harbour Court Marina (N. Miami Beach, Florida), color photograph of rendering (Box 11)
    - Hartley's (Miami, Florida), black and white photograph (Box 11)
    - Hebrew Academy (Miami Beach, Florida), 1927; black and white photograph (Box 11)
    - Herbert's, black and white photographs (Box 11)
    - Hewlett Jewish Center (East Rockaway, New York), black and white photographs (Box 11)
    - Hilton Hotel (Macon, Georgia), 1939; black and white photographs (Box 11)
    - Hoffritz for Cutlery, black and white photograph (Box 11)
    - Holiday Springs Village (Margate, Florida), color photograph of rendering (Oversize 5)
    - Holly (Loredo, Texas), black and white photograph (Box 11)
    - The Hollywood (West End, New Jersey), black and white photograph (Box 11)
    - Hotel Continental (Ecuador), black and white photographs of model (Box 11)
    - Howard Johnson's Motor Lodge (New York, New York), black and white photographs (Box 11)
    - Indies House (Duck Key, Florida)
      - Drawings, drawings include site and floor plans (Oversize 7)
      - Photographs, 1959; undated; black and white (Box 11)
    - Interama, black and white and color photographs of renderings, transparency; possibly the same as the International Trade Center for Miami (Box 11)
    - Interkontinentaler Flughafen Hotel (Zürich, Switzerland), drawings include site plan, floor plans, elevations and interior perspectives (Oversize 7)
    - International Inn (Tampa, Florida)
      - Drawings, includes floor plans and perspective (Oversize 7)
      - Photographs, black and white (Box 11)
    - International Inn (Washington, DC)
      - Drawings, includes elevations and floor plans (Oversize 7)
      - Photographs, black and white (Box 11)
    - International Trade Center for Miami (Miami, Florida), site plans and photostats of elevation; possibly the same as Interama (Oversize 8)
    - Jacksonville Sky Center (Jacksonville, Florida), black and white photographs (Box 11)
    - Jewish Federation office building (Miami, Florida), black and white photographs and black and white photograph of rendering (Box 11)
    - John Forsythe, black and white photographs (Box 11)
    - Kay Jewelers, 1938; 1943; black and white photographs (Box 11)
    - The Kensington (Pompano Beach, Florida), black and white photograph of rendering (Box 11)
    - Lapidus apartment (8th Street), 1940; black and white photographs (Box 11)
    - Lapidus apartment (Miami, Florida), black and white and color photographs (Box 11)
    - Lapidus office (Miami Beach, Florida), color photographs (Box 11)
    - Lapidus office (New York, New York), 1929; 1945,; undated; black and white photographs (Box 11)
    - Lauderdale Seasons (Ft. Lauderdale, Florida), black and white photograph of rendering (Box 11)
    - Lincoln Road Mall (Miami Beach, Florida)
      See also Lincoln Road Mall redesign for related projects by other architects.
      - Photographs, 1959-1960; undated; black and white, includes some photocopies and notes (Box 12)
      - Preservation materials, 1971-1994; undated (Box 12)
    - Loew's Midtown Motor Inn (New York, New York), black and white photographs (Box 12)
    - London Character Shoes, black and white and color photographs (Box 12)
    - Maisel restaurant (Sunny Isles, Florida), black and white photographs (Box 12)
    - Mangel's clothing store, black and white photographs and photocopy (Box 12)
    - Martin's department store (Brooklyn, New York), 1943-1944; undated; black and white and color photographs and photocopy (Box 12)
    - Medical Care Center (St. Petersburg, Florida), black and white photograph of rendering (Box 12)
    - Meridian office building, 1960; black and white photograph (Box 12)
    - Miami Beach, aerial color photograph includes some Lapidus hotels (Oversize 5)
    - Miami Beach Fire Station (Miami Beach, Florida), black and white photographs (Oversize 5)
    - Miami Beach Topa (Miami Beach, Florida), color photograph (Box 12)
    - Musicians' Club of America (Coral Gables, Florida), color photograph of rendering (Box 12)
    - Namm's (The Elm Club) (West End, New Jersey), black and white photograph (Box 12)
    - Nurse's residence, New York Convalescent Home (Brooklyn, New York), black and white photograph (Box 12)
    - Nyack, The Sorrento hotel (Miami Beach, Florida), black and white photograph (Box 12)
    - Oceanside Plaza (Miami Beach, Florida), black and white photograph (Box 12)
    - Olympic building (New York, New York), 1970; black and white photograph (Box 12)
    - Orlando Hotel (Orlando, Florida), black and white photograph of rendering (Box 12)
    - Palm Beach Gardens (Palm Beach, Florida), black and white photograph of rendering (Box 12)
    - Paradise Island Hotel (Nassua, Bahamas), black and white and color photographs and color photograph of rendering (Box 12)
    - Parisian Bootery, 1928; black and white photograph (Box 12)
    - Parker Tower (Hollandale, Florida), black and white photographs and black and white photograph of rendering (Box 12)
    - Peach Tree Battle Towers (Atlanta, Georgia), black and white photograph of rendering (Box 12)
    - Plaza 32 (Miami Beach, Florida), black and white photograph of rendering (Box 12)
    - Ponce de Leon Hotel (San Juan, Puerto Rico), photostats of elevations and floor plans, map of Puerto Rico (Oversize 7)
    - Pool and recreation building (Brooklyn, New York), color photograph (Box 12)
    - Postman's glove and handbag store, 1941; black and white photograph (Box 12)
    - Presidential Towers (New York, New York), black and white photographs (Box 12)
    - Rainbow Shop, 1942; black and white photographs (Box 12)
    - Ray's Dresses, black and white photograph (Box 12)
    - Regal Shoes, 1931; black and white photograph (Box 12)
    - Regency Towers (Miami Beach, Florida), black and white photographs (Box 12)
    - Rivergate Plaza (Miami, Florida), color photographs and black and white and color photographs of renderings (Box 12)
    - Riverside Elementary School (Miami, Florida), color photograph of rendering (Oversize 5)
    - Rock-A-Bye shop, black and white photograph and photocopy (Box 12)
    - Roots Store (Toronto, Canada), color photographs, photocopies, working drawings (Box 12)
    - Royal Coast Condominium (Pompano Beach, Florida), black and white photographs (Box 12)
    - Royal Embassy (Miami Beach, Florida), black and white photographs (Box 12)
    - Sach's (Bronx, New York), black and white photographs (Box 12)
    - El San Juan Hotel (Puerto Rico), black and white photograph (Box 12)
    - Sans Souci Hotel (Miami Beach, Florida), 1949; undated; black and white and color photographs and photocopy (Box 12)
    - Schine Center (Los Angeles, California), 1959; black and white photograph of rendering (Box 12)
    - Seacoast Towers (Miami Beach, Florida), black and white and color photographs, black and white photographs of models and drawings, transparency and article (Box 12)
    - Seagram's offices (New York, New York), 1934; black and white photograph (Box 12)
    - Shaare Zion (Brooklyn, New York), black and white photograph (Box 12)
    - Shadow Mountain (West Virginia), color photograph of rendering, possibly of resort buildings (Box 12)
    - Sheraton Motor Inn (New York, New York)
      - Photographs, 1959-1970; undated; black and white and photocopy (Box 12)
      - Photostats, floor plans (Oversize 7)
    - Sherman Box Tie (New York, New York), 1946; black and white photograph (Box 13)
    - Skyline Motor Inn (Washington, DC), black and white photographs (Box 13)
    - Slatkin's Furs (Brooklyn, New York), black and white photograph (Box 13)
    - Sterling Forest Hotel (Tuxedo Park, New York), drawings include site plan, elevation and floor plan (Oversize 7)
    - South Shore Community Center (Miami Beach, Florida), black and white and color photographs, black and white photographs of model (Box 13)
    - Summit Hotel (New York, New York)
      - Photographs, 1960; undated; mostly black and white, includes color photograph of rendering and photocopy (Box 13)
      - Photostats, floor plans (Oversize 7)
      - Preservation materials, 2004-2007; undated (Box 13)
    - Surfside apartments, black and white photograph (Box 13)
    - Swiss Air Hotel (Zürich, Switzerland), drawings include perspective, site plan and floor plans (Oversize 7)
    - Temple Beth-El, black and white photograph (Box 13)
    - Temple Beth Tfiloh (Baltimore, Maryland), black and white photographs of renderings (Box 13)
    - Temple Judea (Temple Israel?) (Miami, Florida), black and white photograph (Box 13)
    - Terrace Towers (Miami, Florida), black and white photographs and black and white photograph of rendering (Box 13)
    - Toy Center of the U.S.A. (New York, New York), black and white photographs (Box 13)
    - Trelawny Beach Hotel (Jamaica)
      - Photographs, black and white and color (Box 13)
      - Photographs, oversize color photographs of renderings (Oversize 5)
    - Trump Village (Brooklyn, New York), 1966; black and white photographs, transparencies, and photocopies (Box 13)
    - University of Miami, Gussman Concert Hall (Miami, Florida), black and white and color photographs, color photographs of renderings and photocopy (Box 13)
    - University of Miami, School of Business Administration (Miami, Florida), perspective drawings (Oversize 5)
    - Uriss Hilton (New York, New York), 1960; black and white of rendering (Box 13)
    - Variety Children's Hospital (Miami, Florida), black and white and color photographs (Box 13)
    - Vermont & K. Street office building (Washington, DC), black and white photographs (Box 13)
    - Victoria Plaza (Miami Beach, Florida), black and white photograph (Box 13)
    - Villa Fontana, color photographs and negatives (Box 13)
    - Voyager Motel, black and white photograph (Box 13)
    - Wallach's clothing store, black and white photographs (Box 13)
    - Wally Frank Ltd., black and white photograph (Box 13)
    - Watch designs, 2 sketches with matting (Oversize 4)
    - Weeghman's restaurant (New York, New York), 1933; black and white photograph (Box 13)
    - Wise Shoe, black and white photograph (Box 13)
    - Woods of Lauderdale development (Ft. Lauderdale, Florida), color photograph of rendering (Box 13)
    - Unidentified bar, pencil drawing on tracing paper (Oversize 5)
    - Unidentified projects (possibly by Deborah Desilets), notes and sketch of floor plan on mailing envelope (Oversize 5)
    - Miscellaneous
      - Artwork, 1974; 1991,; 2000,; undated; drawing of "The Faces of Israel," paintings and lithograph (?) plates; 2 folders (Oversize 8)
      - Dinnerware, color photographs (unclear whether it was designed by Lapidus) (Oversize 5)
      - Drawings (Oversize 8)
      - Friedman Scans from Morris Lapidus Collection, 02/25/2004; lapidus_70; CD (Box 13)
      - Negatives, 2 folders (Box 13)
      - Permits, 1949-1955 (Box 13)
      - Photocopies (Box 14)
      - Photographs, black and white, includes photographs of renderings, color transparency, and photocopies (Box 14)
      - Sketchbook (Oversize 5)
      - Sketches, 2 folders (Oversize 4)
      - Sketches (Oversize 5)
      - Sketches, 81 items (Oversize 8)
      - Slide lists, 3 folders (Box 14)
      - Slides, 5 folders (Box 15)
      - Slides, 4 folders (Box 16)
      - Watercolor (Oversize 5)
    - Projects by other architects
      - Lincoln Road Mall redesign
        See also Lincoln Road Mall for materials related to Lapidus's original design.
        - Bermello & Associates, 1992 (Box 16)
        - Descam, 1992 (Box 17)
        - Duany & Plater-Zyberk, 1992 (Box 17)
        - Geddes Brecher Qualls Cunningham, 1992 (Box 17)
        - Harries / Héder Collaborative, 1992 (Box 17)
        - J. P. Friedman & Associates, 1992 (Box 17)
        - Lincoln Road Design Team, 1992 (Box 17)
        - Project for Public Spaces, 1992 (Box 18)
        - Raquel Ramati & Associates, 1992 (Box 18)
        - Robert A. M. Stern Associates, 1992 (Box 18)
        - Roma Design Group, 1992 (Box 18)
        - Stair, Wilson A., Jr. (Box 19)
        - Strategic Planning Group, 1992 (Box 18)
        - Thompson & Wood, et al., 1994; master plan report (Box 19)
        - UDA Architects, et al., 1992 (Box 19)
        - Miscellaneous designs, 2008; undated (Box 19)
      - Spear residence, working drawings 1-5, A-1 toA-9, S-1 to S-5 and topographical survey (Oversize 8)
      - St. Regis hotel, 2005; undated (Box 19)
      - Tallahassee Planned Unit Development, 1977; 2002 (Box 19)
      - Miscellaneous, slides (Box 19)
- Writings
  - Bibliographies (Box 20)
  - By Lapidus
    - Articles
      - Published, 1944-1964; 2003,; undated (Box 20)
      - Unpublished, 1933-1967; undated; 3 folders (Box 20)
    - Biographical essays, 2 folders (Box 20)
    - Biographical essays, 2 folders (Box 21)
    - Books
      - An Architect and the American Dream
        - Epilogue (Box 21)
        - Manuscript, 2 folders (Box 21)
      - Architectural Practice and the Business of Architecture (Box 22)
      - An Architecture of Joy, 2 folders (Box 22)
      - Fontainebleau Saga
        - Manuscripts, 2 folders (Box 22)
        - Transcripts of tapes (Box 22)
      - Lilith and the Rabbi
        - Excerpts (Box 23)
        - Manuscripts, 2 folders (Box 23)
      - Publicity (Box 23)
    - Lectures
      Transcripts and videos of lectures can be found under the professional papers series.
    - Plays, 1951-1964; undated (Box 23)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 23)
  - On Lapidus
    - Books
      - Excerpts (Box 24)
      - Miami and its Beaches (Box 24)
      - Publicity (Box 24)
    - Brochures, 2004; undated; published by the Greater Miami Convention & Vistors' Bureau (Box 24)
    - Magazine articles, 1960-1997; 4 folders (Box 24)
    - Magazine articles, 1998-January 2002; 6 folders (Box 25)
    - Magazine articles, December 2004-January 2009; 5 folders (Box 26)
    - Magazine articles, February 2009-December 2010; undated; 4 folders (Box 27)
    - Magazine articles, oversize, 1962-2000 (Oversize 1)
    - Newspaper articles, oversize, 1963-1997; 2 folders (Oversize 1)
    - Newspaper articles, oversize, 1997-2010; undated; 3 folders (Oversize 2)
    - Newspaper articles, photocopies (Box 27)
    - Theses
      - "Morris Lapidus: Architecture as Intentional Nonsense", John Cook (Box 27)
      - "The Upright Jive of Morris Lapidus", 1994; Daniel Tashman (Box 27)
  - On other architects
    - Magazine articles, 1994-2002; undated; 2 folders (Box 29)
    - Newspaper clippings, 2 folders (Oversize 2)
- Deborah Desilets
  - Professional Papers
    - Calendars, 1995-2000; includes many appointments with Lapidus; 2 folders (Box 29)
    - Correspondence, 1980-2008 (Box 29)
    - Hertz, Hal, note attached reads "copies for DD" (Box 29)
    - Lapidus Foundation proposal (Box 29)
    - Lapidus music CD (Box 29)
    - Lapidus video proposals, 1997 (Box 29)
    - Publicity, 1996-2001; undated (Box 29)
    - Publicity compilations on Lapidus, contains notes and articles on Lapidus and his career; 1 folder (Box 29)
    - Publicity compilations on Lapidus, contains notes and articles on Lapidus and his career; 2 folders (Box 30)
    - Resumes (Box 30)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 30)
  - Writings
    - Books
      - An Architecture of Joy, 2010; partial galley copy (essay), annotated, and publicity for book (Box 30)
      - An Architecture of Joy, partial galley copy (photographs), annotated (Oversize 6)
      - The Ritz-Carlton South Beach, galley copy, annotated (Oversize 6)
    - Lectures
      - Georgia Tech lecture (Box 30)
      - "Pressing Style", 1997; 2003; in collaboration with Deborah Desilets (Box 30)
      - Unidentified lecture, 2006 (Box 30)
    - Play - "The Shiksa & the Altacaca", 2001 (Box 30)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 30)
  - Miscellaneous
    - Charlie Rose name badges (Oversize 10)
    - Furniture notebook (Box 31)
    - Galley of untitled book on Herman Miller, annotated (Oversize 6)
    - Knoll Design Symposium booklet, 1999; annotated by Desilets (Box 31)
    - Notes and clippings, 2 folders (Box 30)
    - Notes on dredging and man-made islands
      - Papers (Box 30)
      - 7 Lamps Lapidus, Dredging VO, lapidus_73; CD (Box 30)
      - M Islands Manmade 1920 - 1920s, lapidus_72; CD (Box 30)